-我没杀那个人 迈克尔  -证据显示是你杀的
- I didn't kill that man, Michael. - The evidence says you did.
-有人陷害我  -你发誓
- I was set up. - Swear to me.
我发誓 迈克尔
I swear to you, Michael.
放下手中的武器
Put down your weapon!
我将判那你入狱服刑
I find it incumbent that
斯科菲尔德先生
you see the inside of a prison cell, Mr. Scofield.
我在找个人... 叫林肯·布鲁斯
I'm looking for someone... guy named Lincoln Burrows.
你为什么急着想见布鲁斯
Why you want to see Burrows so bad anyhow?
因为他是我哥哥
Cause he's my brother.
-我要把你救出去  -那不可能
- I'm getting you out of here. - That's impossible.
除非监狱是你设计的 但不是你设计的
Not if you designed the place, it isn't.
你是个让人迷惑的开锁高手
You one mixed-up cracker,
你知道吗
you know that?
成交吗
Are we in business?
现在... 只等时机了
Now... it's all about timing.
斯科菲尔德 你跟传闻中一样漂亮
Scofield. You just as pretty as advertised.
我们什么时候动手
When do we get started?
-我需要你的帮助  -你这是在叫我犯法
- I need your help. - You're asking me to break the law.
是我让你犯错误
I'm asking you to make a mistake.
别锁门
Forget to lock up.
快点
Come on.
我们成功了 迈克
We did it, Mike.
不管最后结局怎样...
However this plays out...
我不后悔
I have no regrets.
迈克尔
Michael!
如果你看到这个的话 说明你安全了
Well, if you're watching this, that means you're safe.
我希望能在你身边
I wish I could be there with you,
但你知道 我没多少时间了
but as you know now, I wouldn't have had much time.
我已做出决定
I made my choice.
我不后悔
I don't regret it.
我们现在自由了
We're free now.
我们自由了
We're free.
自由是要付出代价的
Freedom has a price.
7年前我死了
I died seven years ago.
留下我哥哥...
Left behind a brother...
妻子...
a wife...
和儿子
a son.
但是 死人也会说话
But the dead talk...
如果你仔细倾听
if you listen.
他们就在你身边...
They're there with you...
伸出手...
reaching out...
想告诉你些什么
trying to tell you something.
因为并不是所有的死亡都是一样的
Because not all deaths are the same.
有些是真的
Some are real.
有些只是故事
Some are a story.
问题是...
Question is...
你信不信这个故事
do you believe the story?
死了的那个人
Was the man who died
是你认为的那个人吗
who you thought he was?
死人也会说话
The dead talk...
如果仔细倾听...
if you listen.
还是很合身...
Still tight as...
像蛇蜕的皮一样
scales on a snake.
巴格威尔 你上面肯定有朋友吧
Must have friends in high places, Bagwell.
我不知道像你这种垃圾怎么搞到出狱单的
How a cesspool like you gets his walking papers I'll never know.
你口中的垃圾以前也是模范市民
This cesspool has been a model citizen.
模范 市民
Model citizen.
71.31块
$71.31.
笔记本电脑
Laptop.
一包口香糖 还剩3片
Pack of gum, three pieces.
那个你留着怎么样
How about you keep that?
你带什么进来 就带什么出去
Whatever you bring in, you bring out.
还有最后一封信
And one last piece of correspondence.
我每周替你这种人收十几封信的时候
Something really wrong with the world when I'm receiving
就在想这个世界肯定出毛病了
dozens of letters a week for guys like you.
跟电邮没法比
Nothing compared to the e-mails.
你们这种杀人犯
What is it with you killers
还知道怎么取悦女人吗
that put the satin on women's panties anyhow?
我靠
Lackaday!
布鲁斯
Burrows!
不如你出来
How about you step out and pay us
把欠我们的十万还上怎么样
the hundred grand you owe us?
就当你拒绝了
Take that as a no.
林肯·布鲁斯...
Lincoln Burrows...
拒绝了
says no.
硬汉啊...
Big tough guy...
名声在外
who made it out of the neighborhood.
看看你现在的样子... 又变成了老样子
And look at you now... back to your roots,
跟以前一个样
the way you've always been.
一个付不起欠债的三流小骗子
A small-time crook who can't pay his debts.
我们会找到你的
We're gonna find you, you know,
再把你活剥了
and we're gonna open you up.
林肯小宝贝
Lincolny-linc.
好久不见
All huffin' and puffin'.
别像看垃圾一样看着我
Don't you look at me like I'm trash.
我家整整齐齐 我也身世清白了
My house is in order. I'm clear with the government,
监狱总局 天呐
the D.O.C. And my God.
跟你可不太一样
Doesn't appear to be the same with you.
看看你 完全堕落了
Look at you, all backslid.
你这几年应该发达了啊
You're supposed to be going up in the world as you age,
还是说 你没收到便条
or did you not get the memo?
你不从我的门廊滚下去 我就打爆你的头
You don't get off my deck, I'm gonna crack your skull.
我不会走的
I wouldn't do that.
命运似乎注定了
Seems fate has deigned
要让我们再次联手
to join us at the hip once again,
尽管我们互相看不顺眼
despite our mutual contempt.
看看这个
Have a look-see.
你从哪里拿到的
Where'd you get this?
这周早些时候释放时收到的
Received it on release earlier this week.
没有回信地址
No return address.
要是你敢耍我 我就杀了你
If you're playing me, I'll kill you.
看看上面的邮戳
Take a look at that postmark on that.
我可能很狡猾
I may be a sophisti-cat,
但是没达到
but not so sophisticated
能伪造这些的程度
as to forge something like that.
而且
Besides...
我有什么理由过来
what angle could I possibly have in coming here
跟你说你弟弟
and telling you that it looks like your brother
有可能还活着
might just be alive?
不可能
It's impossible.
我也是这么想的
That's what I thought.
他为什么寄给你
Why'd he send it to you?
我也在这么想
Again, what I thought.
然后我重新看了看这些
And then I gave the words another look-see.
可能这就是答案
Maybe that's the answer.
"借你之手"
"By your hand"
"你会看到子孙的荣光"
"You shall know the glories of your Progeny"
"我们的世界将被
"And our world will be
永远纠正过来"
made right forevermore."
我要知道这是什么意思就见鬼了
Hell if I know what that means.
但就像信是写给我的一样
But just like that envelope's addressed to me,
这些话肯定也是写给我的 肯定是
those words are addressed to me. Got to be!
出去
Get out.
我在跟你合作呢
I'm trying to work with you here.
你弟弟有没有可能还活着
Is there any possible way your brother could've survived?
我弟弟死了
My brother's dead.
那这是谁寄的 为什么寄给我
Th-Then who sent this? And why?
滚
Get out.
起码让我拿走属于我的信
Least let me take my rightful correspondence.
算了 布鲁斯 反正我复印了
Oh, I made a copy, Burrows.
我就知道你还是那个婊子养的混蛋
I knew you'd be the same obstinate son of a beyotch
你一直都是 但我希望你有所改变
you always been, but I'd hoped you'd seen the light.
但你就是你 一直都是这鸟样
But you are what you is and you is what you are.
不过 我还是要告诉你...
Still, I'm telling you...
无论如何命运还是要让我们联手
fate has got us joined at the hip somehow.
哪里飞来的
Where you in from?
芝加哥
Chicago.
芝加哥是个好地方
Love Chicago.
-给你  -多谢 哥们
- There you go. - Thanks, man.
没想到我还能见到你
I didn't think I was ever gonna see you again.
你没来参加我的婚礼
You didn't come to the wedding.
我是说 我明白...我能理解
I mean, I figured I... I get it...
你不希望我嫁给除了你兄弟之外的任何人...
he hates me for marrying someone other than his brother, but...
我过的不太好 萨拉
I haven't been in a good place, Sara.
我的脑子里很乱
My brain, it's... it's been a mess.
所以我一直没露面
That's why I didn't show up.
而且...我不想我侄子看到我这个样子
And... I didn't want my nephew to see me like that.
但现在我没法撒手不管了
But now it's impossible to stay away.
有人开了个无聊的大玩笑
Someone's got a sick sense of humor.
我知道你希望这是真的
I know you want it to be true.
失去弟弟...
Losing a brother...
给你的人生留下巨大的创伤
the massive hole that leaves in your life.
和失去丈夫一样 巨大的创伤
Like the same massive hole losing a husband is.
可能吧
Maybe.
林肯·布鲁斯
Lincoln Burrows?
雅各布
Jacob.
我有几年没见你了
I haven't seen you in what,
-三四年了吧  -是
- three, four years? - Yeah.
林肯叔叔
Uncle Lincoln!
嘿 小家伙
Hey-hey! Buddy!
见到你真是太好了
So good to see you.
你给我带沉没的宝藏了吗
Did you bring me any sunken treasures?
沉没的宝藏
Sunken treasures?
潜水商店
The dive shop.
-巴拿马  -对 我常给他讲
- Panama. - Yeah, I've been telling him stories
我们回国前在那边发生的故事
about being down there before we came back to the States.
你都快变成
You've become kind of like
他心里的传奇英雄了 我给你拿罐啤酒
a mythological hero to him. Let me get some beers.
-我们聊聊  -当然好
- I want to know what you been up to. - Sure, man. Yeah.
好的
Okay.
过来
Come here.
你先去冲个澡 好吗
I want you to go wash up, okay?
然后才能跟你叔叔一起玩
And then you can catch up with your uncle.
他不仅崇拜你
He hasn't just mythologized you.
他还崇拜迈克尔
He mythologizes Michael, too.
他觉得自己像是神的孩子
It's like someone thinking he was born to a god,
一位他从没见过
a god he's never met...
也不存在的神
and who isn't here.
一位再也不可能出现的神
And who never will be again.
我该现实点
I can be pragmatic.
迈克尔病了
Michael was sick.
他病入膏肓
He was terminally sick,
然后去世了
and he died.
萨拉
Sara...
这你又怎么解释
how do you explain that?
这是处理过的照片 林肯
It's Photoshop, Linc,
或者别的什么
or something.
你得考虑到这是哪儿来的
You got to consider the source.
是T-Bag给的
This came from T-Bag.
我知道你希望这是真的
I know you want it to be true.
我也希望
I want it to be true.
今晚约个会吧 模范市民
How about a date tonight, model citizen?
长时间漂流之后
A little well-earned love
一点应得的抚慰
after a long time at sea.
桃乐茜小姐
Miss Dorothy.
从伊利诺斯州奥罗拉省
E-mailing her undying love
发来她永恒的爱
from Aurora, Illinois.
这个呢
How about this one?
"来自尚佩恩坎农·阿朗佐的爱"
"Love Cannon Alonzo in Champaign."
光看名字就让人拒绝
Hop on that just on the name alone.
什么玩意儿
What the hell?
假肢研究中心
Prosthetic research?
你的萨拉很聪明
Smart girl, your Sara.
她说得对
She's right.
我只是太想见你了
I'm just desperate to see your face.
自从你离开后 我的生活就变得一团糟
My life's been a mess ever since you left.
又重操旧业
Fallen back into my old ways.
做一些你不认同的事情
Something you wouldn't tolerate.
可我有进步 迈克尔
But I got good in me, Michael.
我变好了
I got good in me.
只是如果
It'd just be nice if
你能在这儿...帮我找到生活的方向
you were here to... help me find it.
所以..
So... yeah.
"奥杰吉厄岛"
"Ogygia."
告诉我你在哪儿
Telling me where you are.
看来只有这样才能查明真相了
There's only one way to find out.
西奥多·巴格威尔
Theodore Bagwell.
惠特科姆医生
And you're Dr. Whitcombe,
约我晚上九点半秘密见面
the man who invited me to this mystery meeting
这个时候这栋建筑的其他场所都关门了
at 9:30 at night when the rest of the building's closed.
我知道你的过去
I know what you've done.
所以我不想被人看见我和你来往
That's why I don't want to be seen associating with your sort.
我只想知道你叫我来做什么
Just want to know why I'm here, and...
是不是和我在监狱里收到的
if this has anything to do with that special envelope
那封特殊信有关系
I received in the prison.
我不知道什么信
I know nothing about an envelope.
我只能向你介绍我的工作
I can only tell you my work.
定向肌肉神经移植术
Targeted muscle reinnervation.
能用大脑控制假肢
Using the brain to manipulate prosthesis
和长出来的四肢一样
as it were a natural limb.
但是 如此前沿的技术
But as with any cutting-edge work,
往往很难得到资金支持
funding is not easy to find, and yet,
难以置信 我能获得资助
incredibly, I got the grant
一笔巨额匿名资助
in the form of a considerable anonymous grant
但有一个条件
on one condition...
第一个接受手术的人
the first recipient of my procedure...
必须是你
is you.
我能帮你装上
I can equip you
一副完整的 关节灵活的假肢
with a fully articulate prosthetic,
用起来和真的手没什么分别
operationally indistinguishable from a real hand.
所有这些只是因为一项匿名捐赠吗
All of this because of an anonymous donor?
看起来像是有人在操纵你我
Someone seems to have plans for both of us.
我给你预留了周一的手术室
I've reserved an operational lab for Monday
如果你决定了的话
if you decide you are interested.
反正是你的手
It's your hand, ultimately.
借你之手
By your hand,
你会看到子孙的荣光
you shall know glories of your progeny.
什么
What's that?
没什么 医生
Nothing, Doc.
拜托 迈克尔
Come on, Michael.
你一定给我留了什么提示
You must've left me something.
拜托 迈克尔
Come on, Michael.
什么情况
What's going on?
我的天 发生了什么
Oh, my God, what happened?
我不清楚
I'm not sure.
我准备报警
I'm gonna call the police.
哈喽
Hello?
我挖开了迈克尔的墓 他没在里面
I dug up Michael's grave. He's not in it.
他...什么
He... What?
萨拉 刚刚有人想杀我
Sara, someone just tried to kill me.
他们一直都在盯我 伺机行动
They've been watching. They've been watching,
-可能是为了...  -谁要杀你
- probably for... - Who tried to kill you?
从机场开始的 我...
It started at the airport. I...
他们开一辆红色的轿车
There was a... a red sedan.
一路跟着我
It started following me.
然后他们... 他们... 他们
Then they... they... they swapped
换成了一辆...
down to a...
-一辆什么  -一辆皮卡
- What was it? - A pickup.
什么颜色的皮卡
What color was the pickup?
黑色
Black.
怎么了
Why?
萨拉
Sara?
雅各布
Jacob?
怎么了
Yeah.
挂在砖墙的其中一幅画
Behind one of the pictures on the brick wall,
后面有个洞 里面
there's a hole, and there's
-有把枪 你把它拿出来  -什么
- a gun in it. I need you to get it. - What?!
就现在 快点 有人来找我们麻烦了
Right now! Right now! Someone's coming for us!
一把枪 你在说什么 一把枪
A gun? What do you mean, a gun?
迈克
Mike?!
911 你有什么紧急情况
9-1-1. What is your emergency?
有一个持枪入侵者闯入了我的屋子
I have an armed intruder in the house.
你需要你们马上派人来
I need you to send people right away.
没时间了 求你们 派人来
I don't have time. Please, come.
-迈克  -萨拉
- Mike? - Sara?
发生什么了 萨拉
What's going on, Sara?
-妈妈  -过来这边
- Mom? - Come here.
萨拉 萨拉怎么了
Sara? Sara!
屋子里只有我 没别人了
It's just me. There's no one else in the house.
-你想要什么  -进浴缸里去
- What do you want? - Get in the tub.
谁在那里 妈妈 他们想要什么
Who's here, Mom? What do they want?
我也不知道 宝贝
I don't know, baby.
好了 听我说 如果有人从这门进来
Okay, listen to me, if anyone comes
你不要动 好吗
through that door, you don't move, okay?
我会用这个捅他们 你不会受伤的
I will put this through them, and you will not be harmed.
明白了吗 好孩子
You understand? Good boy.
雅克布
Jacob?!
妈妈
Mom.
把所有你能找到的毛巾都拿过来
Go get every towel you can find.
快一点 就现在
Right now, right now.
撑住 雅克布
Please, Jacob.
我估计打到动脉了 保持清醒
Okay. I think it got an artery. Stay with me.
我要你看着我 好吗
I want you to look at me, all right?
别闭上眼睛 也别睡过去
Don't close your eyes and don't go to sleep,
我要你保持着清醒
all right? I'm gonna need you to stay with me.
来辆救护车
I need an ambulance!
他怎么样了
How is he?
子弹差不多射穿了他的股动脉
The shot almost completely severed his femoral artery,
医生在努力让他情况稳定下来
so they're trying to stabilize him.
那他呢
And him?
他才七岁
He's seven.
你还好吗 小迈
How you doing, Mikey?
有事情发生了 对吗
Something's happening, isn't it?
一开始 你出现了
First, you come
然后那个人就闯进了我们家
and that person came in our house.
这事情跟我的生父有关 对吗
It has something to do with my real father, doesn't it?
你为什么这么说
Why do you say that?
因为我可以从妈妈脸上看出来
Because I can see it in her face.
我得和你的叔叔谈一谈
I'm gonna need to talk to your uncle.
我就在那边
I'm gonna be right over there
你可以看到我的
where you can see me. Okay?
发生什么了
What's going on?
我们触发了一些事情
We've awoken something.
一些想被藏起来的 跟迈克有关的事
Something people are trying to hide about Michael.
你弟弟已经死了 林肯
Your brother's dead, Lincoln.
他真的死了吗 那他的尸体在哪
Or is he dead? Where is the body?
那他为什么离开
Then why did he leave?
如果他在外面那么多年
If he's been out there for all of these years,
为什么要抛下自己的儿子
why did he abandon his own son?
你知道我是对的
You know I'm right.
如果不是这样的话这些都不会发生
It wouldn't be like this if something wasn't happening.
-是不会 但是...  -让我们回击吧
- It wouldn't, but... - Let's fight back.
我都不知道我们在和谁拼命
I don't know who we're fighting.
我们去也门 把事情搞清楚
Let's go to Yemen and find out.
去也门 我有个儿子 林肯
To Yemen? I have a son, Lincoln.
我丈夫还在急诊室 现在丢下他们
My husband's in the ER. Right? Look, leaving them is exactly
才是我最不应该做的事情
the wrong thing for me to do right now.
女士 你们可以进去看他了
Ma'am. He's ready to see you.
等一下
One second.
我会去的
I'll do it.
我要去也门
I'll go to Yemen.
你特么一点都不了解也门
You don't know a damn thing about Yemen.
那我就去找个了解也门的人
I'll find someone who does.
再见了 小迈
See ya, Mikey.
我羡慕你
I envy you.
你完全改变了你的生活
You changed your life around.
我已经厌倦了不检点的生活了
A man gets tired of living a profligate life.
所以我参加了圣战 真正的圣战
So I took up jihad. Real jihad,
不是你在新闻上看到的那些疯狂举动
not that madness that you see on the news.
存在于内心的圣战
War within.
洗心革面的内心交战
The spiritual struggle to clean up your act.
追寻并且供奉真主
Finding and serving God.
挺不错的 哥们
That's good, man.
这世界需要这个 林肯
The world needs it, Linc.
我是说我们... 我们很渺小
I mean we're... we're small here
但我们做力所能及的
but we do what we can
去帮助中东的和平努力
to help the peace efforts in the Middle East.
在这里致力于反激进运动
Working on anti-radicalization campaigns here at home.
像我所说的 那种斗争
Like I said, the struggle.
这就是我在这儿的原因
That's why I'm here.
如果我要去也门
If I needed to get to Yemen,
有什么你可以帮我的吗
that something you could help me with?
我以为他已经死了
I thought he was dead.
大家都这么觉得
So did everyone.
但是 奥杰吉厄岛监狱
But Ogygia?
那是关重案犯
I mean, that's for heavy hitters,
以及政治犯的地方
political prisoners.
还在也门 情况不可能更糟了
In Yemen, it doesn't come any worse.
你知道要让人相信他还活着有多难吗
I mean, do you know what it would take to stage a death?
更不用说要把这个大活人
Not to mention keeping a man who is not dead
在眼皮底下藏七年
under the radar for seven years.
一定是一些非常有权有势的人
Some very powerful players.
萨义德 你了解这个清真寺吗
Sayed, what do you make of this mosque right here?
阿克萨清真寺 是萨那主要的几个清真寺之一
Aksa Mosque. It's one of the main ones in Sana'a.
非常醒目
It's very distinct.
看起来 从监狱可以
Sightlines seem pretty consistent
不受阻挡地看到清真寺
with what it would probably be from the prison to the mosque.
现在 我告诉你 这照片属实
Now, you ask me, that photo's legit.
那我弟弟就在这座建筑里面
Then that's the building my brother's in.
最简单的确认方法就是打给监狱问问
Easiest way to find out is to call the prison and ask.
迈克·斯科菲尔德
Mafi Michael Scofield.
谢谢
Shukran.
那里没有人叫迈克·斯科菲尔德
There's no Michael Scofield.
去网上找找他的照片
Punch up an image from the Internet.
迈克·斯科菲尔德
Michael Scofield.
把照片发给监狱
Send it to the prison.
可能他用了其他的名字
Maybe he's under a different name.
听着 林肯
Listen, Linc,
我得说一下
I got to say something, man.
你得冷静一下
Man, you got to slow your roll.
也门正处于内战之中
Yemen is in a civil war.
整个国家都快要土崩瓦解了
They're really close to collapse.
不可能任由一个拿着美国护照的白人
It's no place for a white man with an American passport,
在没有阿拉伯人命令的情况下 就这么出现在也门
no command of Arabic, to just show up on a whim.
但显然 我弟弟就这样干了
And yet, apparently, my brother did.
找到照片了 是你弟弟
Got a picture. Your brother's intake photo
福克斯河监狱的入狱照
from the Fox River Penitentiary.
这是他驾驶证照片
Here's his DMV photo
这还有一张 从他以前上班地方的网站找到的
and here's a photo from his old workplace Web site.
那不是他
It's not him.
都不是他
None of them are.
有人想把他的记录全部抹掉
Someone's erasing him from history.
-林肯 你要去哪  -酒店 去拿我的行李
- Lincoln, where are you going? - Hotel, to grab my stuff,
-然后去机场  -听着
- then the airport. - Listen.
你不会真要去也门吧
You're not going to Yemen.
-阻止我  -你熬不过三天的
- Stop me. - You won't make it three days.
我们得走正规渠道
We need to go through the proper channels.
正规渠道
The proper channels?
有人想要清除他的存在
Someone's erasing his existence.
是谁干的 谁有这个能力
Who does that? Who has that ability?
我跟你说 迈克尔准是
I'm telling you, Michael's caught
惹上大麻烦脱不开身了
in the middle of something big.
如果他没脱不开身呢
What if he's not caught in the middle?
你什么意思
What are you saying?
迈克尔从来没上过谁的当
Michael has never been anyone's sucker.
他一直都掌控局势 一直都是
He's always been in control. Always.
你的意思是他亲手策划了自己的假死吗
You saying he faked his own death?
我的意思是
I'm saying you need to look
在你身陷其中之前
at all of the possibilities
睁大眼睛看看所有的可能性
before you walk into a war zone.
我之前不确定你会不会来
I wasn't sure you'd come.
人有时要向命运屈服
Sometimes a man has to surrender to fate.
来看看还有什么在等着他
See what it has in store for him.
我们需要给你做麻醉
We'll need to put you under.
不不不 我不做全麻的 朋友
No, no, no. I don't do general anesthetic, compadre.
对于这种手术进程 全麻是强制性的
It's mandatory for a procedure like this.
你得原谅我
You'll forgive me
我无法就这么失去意识
if I have a problem lying unconscious
躺在你的装置上 看着你在我面前拿着利器
before a man with sharp items at his disposal.
这手术不全麻做不了
It cannot be done without a general anesthetic.
我以前做过的 朋友
Oh, I've done it before, friend.
那你看看你现在什么样
And look what it got you.
别在我昏迷期间干任何不正当的事儿 不然我...
You do anything untoward to me while I'm under and I'll...
得罪谁我都不想得罪你
You are the last man I'd run afoul of.
懂了吗
Okay?
命运啊 你个故弄玄虚的婊子
Oh, fate, you mysterious bitch.
你为何要这样对我
Why you doing this to me?
-干洗的  -衣服不错
- Dry cleaning. - Nice jacket.
谢谢 先生
Thank you, sir.
再见
Have a good day.
你他妈为啥揍我呀
What the hell was that for?
苏克雷 你他妈在这干什么
Sucre, what the hell are you doing here?
C-Note跟我说了
C-Note told me what's going on.
他让你来劝我别去吗
He tell you to talk me out of it?
不 我要跟你去
No. I'm coming with you.
你不准来
You're not coming.
迈克尔是我最好的朋友 他要是活着
Michael's my best friend. If he's alive,
他要是有麻烦 我想尽一份力啊
if he's in trouble, I want to help.
你就没工作什么的要做吗
Don't you have a job or something?
有啊 在个野船上 不是什么好活儿
Yeah, on a tramp. Not great work,
因为我有前科嘛
but hey, I'm an ex-con, right?
流浪者[Tramp有不定期船的意思 也有流浪汉的意思]
Tramp?
没错 我开她开了有一阵了[我上她有一阵了]
Yeah, I've been riding her for a while.
你是干什么的 拉皮条的吗
What are you, a pimp?
啥 不不不
What? No. No, no, no.
野船是指自由货船
A tramp is a freelance cargo ship.
我们去香港 西班牙 布宜诺斯艾利斯
We go to Hong Kong, Spain, Buenos Aires,
基本上就是老板让去哪我们就去哪
basically wherever the boss tells us.
腐败的老混球
Corrupt son of a bitch.
那我建议你回到你的船上去
Well, I suggest you get back on that tramp,
-因为你不准跟我走  -我告诉你 我能帮上忙
- 'cause you're not coming. - I'm telling you, I can help!
听着 这是中东
Listen to me, this is the Middle East.
世事变迁 我现在是国际杀手了
Lots has changed. I'm an international hitter now.
一个善谈的人
A raconteur.
我觉得那词儿你可能会错意了
I don't think that means what you think it means.
别说的像我不懂法语似的 我会说法语
Don't speak to me like I don't know French, I know French.
我还是棕色人种 这才是重点
And I'm brown, that's something.
我在那边要比你更
I'll fit in better over there
能融入社会 白雪
than you will, snowflake.
我觉得我之前说
I decided I was wrong when I said
你三天之内必死说错了
you would be dead inside of three days.
你到那 一天之内就一命呜呼了
You go over there, you'll be dead inside of one.
但是我一起去的话 我认识
But with me, we have people at the mosque
那边清真寺的人
that have worked over there,
有合法关系的人
people with legal connections
能帮我们进那监狱
that can get us inside of that prison.
等等 你的意思不会是他就能去吧
Hold on. You're not saying he gets to go.
他也没比我黑多少啊
He's not any browner than I am.
不会吧
No?
我在伊拉克的时候
I managed to pick up a little Arabic
学了点阿拉伯语
while I was serving in Iraq.
乘坐39号航班飞往肯尼迪国际机场经停也门的
This is the final boarding call for Flight 39
旅客们你们好 这是本次航班的最后一次登机通知...
to JFK, connecting to Yemen. This is the final boarding...
听着 伙计
Listen, man.
我以后会需要你的
There's gonna be a time when I'm gonna need you.
你最好找着他
You better find him.
到时候你最好打电话通知我
And you better call me when you do.
我会的
I will.
你真有关系啊
You really got contacts?
关系的关系
Contacts with contacts.
可以直接跟着他们去洗手间
Could just follow 'em into the bathroom,
把他堵在一个单间里然后干掉
ragdoll him in one of stalls and be done with it.
那我们还要处理尸体
Then we'd have a body to deal with.
我们想让他绝对地
And we want him utterly
完全地这个世界上消失
and irrevocably gone from this world.
一点渣都不剩
Where no amount of digging will bring him back.
我们是唯一的入境人员
We're the only ones coming into the place.
是啊 这个国家要完了
Yeah, the country's falling apart.
所有人都想走
Everyone wants out.
中间人是谁来着
Who's that contact again?
一个叫希巴的女人
A woman named Sheba.
我们的接手人
Our handler.
她帮我们追踪那些
She helps us track Americans that come in
入境对抗圣战的美国人
to fight the jihad fight.
欢迎加入内战
Welcome to the civil war.
富兰克林先生
Mr. Franklin,
希巴小姐让我来接你们
Ms. Sheba sent me to collect you.
你好
As-salaam alaikum.
Wa alaikum as-salaam.
这边 两位 请跟我来
This way, gentlemen. Follow me.
也门特别危险
Yemen very dangerous.
你永远不得而知人们是敌是友
You never know who's enemies, who's friends.
每个人都在背后
Everyone scratching
互相搞鬼
each other's backs.
伊斯兰国开始攻击城市了
ISIL is starting to attack the city.
他们已经在沙漠地区准备了数月
They have been building up out in the desert for months.
要是...要是他们攻下了城市
If they... take the city,
他们就会杀光所有的世俗主义者
they will kill all the secularists,
建立伊斯兰法教
install Sharia law.
你知道的
You know.
你看起来一点也不担心啊
You don't seem worried.
我也抓心挠肝啊 我的朋友
I scratch backs, too, my friend.
不不不不 这地方不对
No, no, no, no. This isn't right.
等一下
Wait a minute,
这不是我们要去的地址
this-this isn't the address.
-我去抽个烟  -别 不 你回来
- I get cigarettes. - No, no, you don't.
带我们去正确的地址 现在
You take us straight to the address right now!
我得抽个烟
I-I get cigarettes.
林肯 这是个圈套
Linc, this is a setup.
我们现在得拿到你的包
We're gonna grab your bag now.
美国监狱系统问候你们 混球们
Greetings from the U.S. Prison system, bitches.
那是什么
What is it?
我们被人设计了
Someone set us up.
快走
Come quickly.
不然我们都得死
Or we'll all be dead!
走 走 她是我们的人
Go, go. She's one of us.
快点 拿上包 走
Come on, grab your bag. Come on, let's go!
你怎么找到我们的
How did you find us?
机场的一个眼线说你们上错了出租车
A contact at the airport saw you get into the wrong taxi.
你们应该庆幸我找到了你们
You're lucky I found you.
这里的人比较激进
This is very radicalized neighborhood.
不管是谁设计了你们 这招也真够高明了
Whoever set you up couldn't have set you up in a worse way.
把你的手机扔出去
Throw your phones out the window.
我不想被任何人追踪
I don't want anyone tracking us.
快点
Do it!
希巴 这是林肯
Sheba, this is Lincoln.
林肯... 她是希巴
Lincoln... Sheba.
你已经健全了 巴格威尔先生
You've been made whole, Mr. Bagwell.
你可以走了
You're free to go.
除非你先告诉我 你在我身体里植入了什么
Not till you tell me what you've put in me.
你感到不安 对吗
You feel an unease, do you?
我想你从出生开始就活在不安中 对吗
I'd venture that's what's always been in you since birth.
你的灵魂 我只是给你装上了机械手
Your soul. I just put the hardware into you.
只有你能操控它
You're the thing that runs it.
-这是谁安排的...  -没有人
- Who's behind... - Nobody!
没有人在背后安排
Nobody's behind this.
什么意思
What does that mean?
我只有一个单词 就这些
I got a single word. That's it.
就是... 我的资助人用一个单词代表他们
Just... my benefactors ID'd themselves by a single word.
奥提斯
Outis.
我查了这个单词
I looked it up.
它在希腊语中代表着"没有人"
It's Greek for "Nobody."
这就是你的资助人 巴格威尔先生
That's who your benefactor is, Mr. Bagwell.
没有人
Nobody.
好了
Okay.
这是谁
Who's this?
奥马尔在奥杰吉厄监狱有内线
Omar has connections in Ogygia Prison.
他可以安排一次探监
He says he can arrange a visit.
意思是迈克尔在那吗
That mean Michael's in there?
那里有个美国人的情况和你弟弟
There's apparently an American in there matching
非常吻合
your brother's description.
只是还有一件事情
There's just one thing.
安排这样的探视很难 非常难
Arranging such a visit is hard. Very difficult.
-需要付出代价  -钱不是问题
- Comes at a price. - Money's not a problem.
不要钱
Not money.
你的护照
Your passport.
我的护照
My passport?
什么...
What, did...
-你想压着它吗  -不 我就要它
- you want to hold it? - No. Straight trade.
你的护照换探监机会
Visit for your passport.
美国护照在这里像黄金一样值钱
U.S. Passport is like gold here.
只需要一点手脚 它就是通往自由的机票了
A few changes, and it can be a ticket to freedom.
别换 林肯
Don't do it, Linc.
我知道情况不理想 但是...
I know it is not ideal, but...
这是也门现在最实际的境况了
ideals as of right now are history in Yemen.
没有护照
You cannot get out of the country
你别想离开这个国家
without a passport.
别换
Don't do it.
阿拉保佑...
Inshallah...
你很快就能见到你弟弟
you will see your brother soon.
我告诫过自己 绝不再踏足任何一座监狱
I told myself I'd never step foot in another prison.
等我们离开这座监狱后再开始
As long as we walk out of it.
没有迈克尔·斯科菲尔德这个人
There's no Michael Scofield.
这是为了骗我护照吗
It was a scam to get my passport.
奥马尔是我最信任的一个眼线
Omar is one of my most trusted operators.
听着 女士 在这个国家
Listen, lady. Trust doesn't
信任似乎并没什么鸟用
seem to mean a whole lot in this country.
给我一点时间 好吗
Give me a second, okay?
我会想办法解决这事的
I'll figure out a way to work this thing out.
照片呢
An image.
他们寄给你的那张
Right? The one that they sent to you?
-哦 对  -你带了吗
- Oh, yeah, yeah. - Do you have it?
看
Look.
这个
There.
坎尼尔·奥提斯
Kaniel Outis.
对 坎尼尔·奥提斯 他在这吗
Yes, Kaniel Outis. Is he here?
他说 照片里的人在这里
He says, yes, the man in the picture is here
我们能见到他 不过只是因为是希巴带我们来的
and we can see him, but only 'cause we're dealing with Sheba.
你怎么知道那个名字的
Why did you say that name?
在我弟弟的夹克上
Because of my brother's jacket.
还以为你们是站在真主这边的
Thought you were on the right side of God on this.
希巴 别走 希巴...
Sheba. No, hey, hey. Sheba...
嘿
Hey.
坎尼尔·奥提斯可是个知名的恐怖分子
Kaniel Outis is a big-time terrorist.
他在这里被判了谋杀罪
They got him in here for murder.
他和伊斯兰国合作
He's been working with ISIL
试图推翻政府
trying to take down the government.
行了 C
Come on, C.
你知道迈克尔不可能干那些事
You know that's not Michael.
好吧 不管他是谁...
Well, whoever he is...
...我们马上就能见到他了
...we're about to meet him.
我爸爸是个怎样的人
What was my father like?
我真正的爸爸
My real father.
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德...
Michael Scofield...
...他就像一场风暴
...was like a storm.
相机准备好
Grab the camera.
我要证明他还活着
I want to prove he's alive.
他很迷人
He was beautiful
惊人
and frightening
神秘
and mysterious.
在湛蓝的天空中呼啸而来
And he would show up in your life
出现在你的生命中
out of the clear blue sky
但转眼就销声匿迹
and then he would disappear just as quickly.
但是 风暴会卷土重来的
But storms, they can come back.
对吧
Can't they?
问题是 回来的风暴
Question is, if they come back,
是原来的风暴
is it the same storm,
还是已经变了
or has something changed?
迈克尔
Michael.
新纹身
New tats.
新的是什么意思
What do you mean, new?
我们来救你出去
We're gonna get you out of here.
我的名字不是迈克尔
My name isn't Michael.
我也不认识你
And I don't know who you are.
抱歉
Sorry.
警卫 带我回牢房
Guard, take me back to the cell.
迈克尔
Michael.
迈克尔 跟我说话 迈克尔...
Michael, talk to me. Michael...
迈克
Mike.
迈克 你在做什么 该死的
Mike! What are you doing, damn it?!
电影淘淘
WWW.DYTTBD.COM
更多电影美剧尽在（电影淘淘 www.dyttbd.com）